Guide to the John Casper Branner, President of Stanford University, Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Casper Branner, president of Stanford University, papers
1913-1917
SC0065
Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922.
5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1969.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
BIOGRAPHY
John Casper Branner, the first professor to be named at the new Stanford University in 1891, served as professor of geology at Stanford as well as executive head of the Geology Department. He later served as vice president of Stanford (1898-1913) and president of Stanford (1913-1915) and professor emeritus (1915-1922). He died on March 1, 1922.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This collection consists of the correspondence of John Casper Branner while he was the President of Stanford University, 1913-1915. The correspondence is concerned with Stanford as a whole and the various departments of the University.
Arrangement note
The collection has been arranged according to subject or department, and chronologically within each department.
Access Terms
Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Presidents.;; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- "A", 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic Secretary, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adams, E.D. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Adams, Maxwell, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Advisory Board, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Alcohol question, 1913-14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alumni Association, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Announcement notices, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Anti-vivisection, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Applied Mathematics (Astronomy), 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Appointment Letters (miscellaneous), 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Arboretum, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Arboretum, Cemetery, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Arnold, Ralph, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Art, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Arts and Sciences, School of, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Association of American Colleges, 1914-16 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Association of American Universities, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Associated Students of Stanford University (ASSU), 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Athletics, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- "B", 1913-14 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "B", 1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Barber, Wm. B. Loan Fund, 1913-1915 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Barrows, Albert (Librarian, U.C. Berkeley), 1914 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Belgian Relief, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Berner, August, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bonnheim Memorial Fund, 1913-1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bookstore, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Botany, 1913-1915 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Branner Inauguration, Jordan retirement, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Business Office, 1913-14 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Business Office, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "C", 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "C", 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- California Academy of Sciences, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Campus School, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Carnegie Foundation, 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Carnegie (miscellaneous), 1915 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Carnot Medal-Debate, (Cemetery--see Arboretum, Cemetery), 1913 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Chemistry, 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Civil Engineering, 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Civil Service Commission, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Committee on Delinquent Scholarship, 1913, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Committee on Graduate Study, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Committee on Loans, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Commonwealth Club, 1913-14 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Cranks, 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Crothers, George E., 1914 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- "D", 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Davis Horace, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Dayal, Har, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Dean of Women, 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Degrees conferred, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- "E", 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Economics, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Education, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Eells, Charles P., 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Electrical Engineering, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Encina Club, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Engineering (general), 1914-1915 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- English, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Entomology, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Everman, Barton W., 1914-1915 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "F", 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Faculty Housing, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Founder's Day, 1914-1915 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Fraternities, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- "G", 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Geology and Mining, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- German, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Golf Course, 1914-1915 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Graduate Manager, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Grant, Joseph Donohue, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Greek, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Guerard, Albert, 1913-14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- "H", 1913-14 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Hilmer (German Dept.), 1915 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- History, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Hoover, Herbert, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Hopkins, Timothy, 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- "I", 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Ichihashi, Yamato, 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Interior, Dept. of, Bureau of Education, 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- "J", 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Jordan, David Starr, 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Junior College Matters (Box 6, Folder 6)
- "K", 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Kellogg, V.L. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- "L", 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Lagunita Tract, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Lathrop, Charles, 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Latin, 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Law, 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Lieb, S.F., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Library, 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- "M", 1913-14 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "M", 1915 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Math, 1913-1915 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Mechanical Engineering, 1913-1915 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Medical School, 1913-1915 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Medical School Anatomy, 1913-1915 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Medical School Bacteriology, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Medical School Bacteriology, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Medical School Bacteriology, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Memorial Church, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Metallurgy, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Meyer, Martin A., Rabbi, 1913,1915 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Microscopes, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Minerology, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Military Training, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Museum, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- "N", 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- National Tax Assoc., 1913-14 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Newhall, W. Mayo, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Nobel Peace Prize, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- "O", 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- "P", 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Pacific Grove, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Panama-Pacific International Expo., 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Philosophy, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Physical Education - Women, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Physical Training - Men, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Physics, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Physiology, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Post Office, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- President's Report, 1913-14 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Presidential Search, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Psychology - Psychical Research, 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Public Exercises, 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Public Health, 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Publicity, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Quad, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- "R", 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Registrar, 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Roble Hall, 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Romanic Languages, 1913-1915 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- "S", 1913 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- "S", 1914 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "S", 1915 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Sabbaticals, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Skinner, Macy M. (Scandal), 1914 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Sociology, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Sloss, Leon, 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Stanford Inn, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Stanford Seal and Motto, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Stanford, T.W., 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Stanford Union, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Stanford Villa Tract, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Student Affairs, 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Student Guild, 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Superintendent, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- "T", 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Taft, William H., 1915 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Tax Assoc., National, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Tax, Income, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Telephone Service, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Trustees, Board of, 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- "U", 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- University Press, 1913-1915 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- "V", 1913-1915 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Vice-President, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Vocational Training, 1913-1915 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- "W", 1913 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- "W", 1914 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- "W", 1915 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- War Relief (Box 11, Folder 7)
- West Memorial Lectures, 1913, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Wheeler, Benjamin Ida, 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Wilson, Woodrow, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- World War I, 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- "Y, ", 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- YMCA, 1913-1915 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- "Z", 1913-1915 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Zoology, 1913-1915 (Box 11, Folder 15)